jryanzelling@gmail.com EMAIL 931.787.3412 CELL

Position Applying For: DICE

John Zelling

Senior Technologist

John Zelling

3451 Desert Cliff St Unit #103 Las Vegas, NV 89129 931.787.3412 jryanzelling@gmail.com 11 JANUARY 2016

ATTN: Technical Recruiter

Recruiting Agency Office of Recruiter 555 5th Street Palo Alto, CA 94301

Dear Hiring Manager,

From January of 2009 to October of 2012 I was employed at the City of Palo Alto in the Public Works Department. I worked on many successful projects independently across three departments. After a few years attending training programs and colleges, I am very interested in returning to a full time position that is fun and challenging. I believe that the job posting is a very good fit that would enable me to achieve this goal.

Attached is my resume that summarizes my qualifications for this position. My experience, background, and education is closely aligned with the requirements. I am a candidate who is passionate and can communicate complex technical ideas to everybody. I feel that I could be a valuable contributor to the team.

I sincerely appreciate the opportunity to be considered. I look forward to discussing the position with you. I hope to find an exciting opportunity.

Sincerely,

John Zelling

John Ryan Zelling Page 1 of 4

Position Applying For: DICE

Technical Skills

- Formal Training/Certifications: Certified Composites Technician, Carbon Fiber Composites, OSHA 30, Forklift, Overhead Crane, Fanuc Robot Operations, First Aid CPR AED, Lean Manufacturing, R Programming, Java Programming, SQL, Selenium, Software Quality Assurance, Web Technology, Software Test Automation, Software Web Application Testing, Black Box Testing, AutoCAD Civil 3D, Autodesk Revit Programmer, G-code, CNC
- **Software Proficiency**: R/Shiny, Python, Ruby, Bash, Mathematica, Android SDK, HTML, Javascript, XML, CSS, SQLite, NoSQL, Safari, Chrome, Mozilla, IE, Word, Excel, PowerPoint, MS Project, Adobe Creative Suite, Photoshop, Illustrator Graphic Design, Mac OS, Android, Windows, Linux, Unix, C++, GNU, AutoCAD

Professional Experience

HCR ManorCare - Toledo, OH IT Security Analyst

07/2016 - 09/2016

- Developed SQL data browser application used for Security Data researchers, eliminated SQL queries with GUI.
- Maintained Linux server to host web applications.
- Developed web application for data analysis and visualizing security within network databases.

Freelance, Various Positions

01/2013 - 12/2015

- Audio Transcription Automation for Production Company.
- Computer Systems Amazon EC2 Administration. Manage Linux/Windows servers for various web applications.

City of Palo Alto – Palo Alto, CA Surveying Engineering Assistant

01/2009 - 10/2012

- GIS data collection and processing using GPS, AutoCAD Civil 3D
- Use of modern mapping technology to create engineering drawing
- Accurately measure and build construction staking and design projects

City of North Las Vegas - N Las Vegas, NV 06/2003 - 01/2009 Engineering Technician

- AutoCAD Design and Project Management support in Engineering Design Group.
- GIS system inputs and development.

John Ryan Zelling Page 2 of 4

jryanzelling@gmail.com EMAIL 931.787.3412 CELL

Position Applying For: DICE

Education

Allegheny College – Meadville, PA 06/1995 - 12/1999

B.Sc. Mathematics

Pellissippi St Comm College - Knoxville, TN 01/2015 - 06 / 2015

Certificate in Electrical Engineering Technology and Sustainability Education (3.8 GPA)

Activities: FANUC Robot Operations Certification 5/17/2015, FANUC Handling Tool Operation and Programming Certification 5/17/2015, Programmable Logic Controllers (PLC) Programming, Data Acquisition, Sensors, Robotics, Industrial Automation, Fanuc Programming, Labview Programming, Microcomputer Architecture, Electric Engineering, Sustainability, LEED GA

Tennessee Tech University – Knoxville, TN 06/2014 - 01/2015

Finished semester towards BFA Fibers and Metals (4.0 GPA)

Activities: Screen print, Block Print, Shibori, Painting on fabric, Sewing, Weaving, Silk, Cotton, Wool; CAD Design, Illustration, Adobe Illustrator, Photoshop; Blacksmithing, Metalsmithing, Goldsmithing, Jewelry Manufacturing.

Roane State Community College 09/2013 - 09/2014

Advanced Manufacturing Technician Training (AMTEC)

Activities: First Aid CPR Certification 11/19/2013, Lean Manufacturing Certification 1/31/2014, OSHA 30 Hour Certification 10/31/2013, Forklift Operations Certification 2/3/2014, Overhead Crane Safety and Operation Certification 2/4/2014, Basic Plumbing (40 hours certification), Basic Measuring and Machining (80 hours certification), Electrical Wiring and Maintenance (80 hours certification), Carbon Fiber/Composite Materials Fundamentals 5/23/2014, Fundamentals of Solar/Energy Efficiency 6/6/2014, Quality Assurance/Quality Control Certification 1/24/2014.

Semester of Advanced Composites Training at Oak Ridge National Lab ORNL (3.5 GPA)

Activities: ACMA Certified Composites Technician (CCT-VIP certification) 8/6/2014, Carbon Fiber, Glass, Kevlar, Woven, Nonwoven, Manufacturing, 3D Printing, Solidworks

National University - Las Vegas, NV 01/2007 - 01/2012

Finished 58.5/60 Credits towards M.Sc. Systems Engineering (3.3 GPA)

Activities: Agile, DOD, Software Engineering, PMP, IEEE, Microsoft Project, Resource, Budget, Strategy

College of Southern Nevada - Las Vegas, NV 01/2002 - 01/2007

Finished all courses Associate Science, Building Info Systems (3.3 GPA)

John Ryan Zelling Page 3 of 4

jryanzelling@gmail.com EMAIL 931.787.3412 CELL

Position Applying For: DICE

Volunteer Work

- Spontaneous Volunteer at American Red Cross, 2015
- Programming Instructor at Hackthefuture.org and CodorDojo Silicon Valley, 01/2009 -12/2013
- Operations Volunteer at Hacker Dojo Mountain View, 01/2009 12/2013
- QCon Conference Crew, 11/2012

Excellent References Available

John Ryan Zelling Page 4 of 4